phamgalang@gmail.com
Portfolio: www.glenrage.com
Github: github.com/glenrage

GALANG (Glen)

PHAM

"I am passionate and prideful about my work no matter the job or task and believe expectations are meant to be exceeded."

SUMMARY

Driven professional with broad technical and soft skill sets who thrives in agile, fast paced environments. 8 years of military experience has instilled leadership, communication, teamwork, and tenacity. Known for ability to meet deadlines and translate ideas into testable, maintainable, readable and reliable code.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Fit-chievements Full Stack Application, Solo Developer github.com/glenrage/fit-chievements

Full stack interactive social media SPA where users can upload and post fitness related achievements. Wrote algorithms to solve complex problems. Built with React, Redux. Scalable, RESTful API built with Node, Express, MongoDB.

Trance Trader Client Application, Solo Developer github.com/glenrage/trance-trader

Stock Market Portfolio app that simulates stock trades with updated portfolio data displaying profits, losses and total portfolio value. Built with React.

Equi-Gallery-VR Full Stack Application, Team Developed github.com/glenrage/Equi-Gallery-VR

Full stack SPA that allows photographers to create a personalized gallery to upload 360* photos & view them in Virtual Reality. Built with Angular, Node.

Effort Manager API Server Application, Team Developed github.com/CF-8-week-challenge/effort-manager

Lead developer in creating RESTful API for an iOS development team for a fitness app that tracks daily challenges with members organized in groups.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Oct 2016 - Present Full Stack Web Developer

Self Taught / Code Fellows, Seattle, WA

Learned Advanced Software Development in JavaScript. Implemented industry's best practices in writing quality, maintainable code and development processes. Integrated data through back end services and frameworks.

2006 - 2014 U.S Air Force (Supervisor, MX Data Analyst)

McChord AFB, WA, Worldwide multiple

Led and supervised aircraft maintenance teams on multiple deployments to hazardous combat zones. Performed maintenance data analysis in GO-81 to efficiently reduce unnecessary maintenance tasks by 20%.

EDUCATION

Feb - June 2017 Full Stack Web Development Intensive

Code Fellows, Seattle, WA

2009 - 2013 Bachelor of Science in Technical Management

Embry - Riddle Aeronautical University - Daytona Beach, FL

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

JavaScript ES6 / jQuery HTML5 / CSS / SASS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Core

Object Oriented (OOP) & Functional Programming MVC / SPA RESTful API / AJAX Continuous Integration Test Driven Development Deployment(Heroku, AWS) Algorithms & Data Structures

Framework/Database

Angular

React / React Native

Redux

Express

Node

Passport Authentication

BootStrap

MongoDB

PostgresSQL

Testing Frameworks

Mocha / Chai Jasmine / Karma BrowserStack

Systems/Tools

Git version control AWS Webpack / Babel

SPOKEN LAN-GUAGES

English (Fluent)
Vietnamese (Fluent)